<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>AFO AI Feed Digest</title>
  <link href="https://github.com/tenki/afo" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://github.com/tenki/afo" rel="self"/>
  <id>https://github.com/tenki/afo</id>
  <updated>2026-01-06T15:20:21.579Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Automatic summaries generated from Feeds.opml sources.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <title>Countdown To New Adventures (January 2026 Wallpapers Edition)</title>
    <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2025/12/desktop-wallpaper-calendars-january-2026/" rel="alternate"/>
    <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2025/12/desktop-wallpaper-calendars-january-2026/</id>
    <updated>2025-12-31T09:00:00.000Z</updated>
    <published>2025-12-31T09:00:00.000Z</published>
    <author>
      <name>Articles on Smashing Magazine — For Web Designers And Developers</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">Smashing Magazine&apos;s January 2026 collection offers 17 free desktop wallpapers in multiple resolutions from international artists, featuring winter themes and motivational designs.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;------&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;# Summary&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Smashing Magazine continues its 14+ year tradition of releasing free monthly desktop wallpapers with the January 2026 collection, featuring 17 unique designs from international artists. The curated collection spans diverse themes including winter imagery (&quot;Winter Magic At Home&quot;), motivational messages (&quot;Start Somewhere,&quot; &quot;Be Awesome Today&quot;), wildlife and nature scenes (&quot;Squirrel Appreciation Day,&quot; &quot;Peaceful Mountains&quot;), and playful illustrations like &quot;Moonwalker&quot; and &quot;Yogabear.&quot; The magazine maintains editorial independence by not influencing design themes, allowing global contributors from Spain, Serbia, the US, France, Belgium, and India to freely express their creative vision. Each wallpaper is available in multiple resolutions with optional calendar integration, aiming to boost productivity and refresh workspaces during the winter season.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;------&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Key sections:&lt;br/&gt;[1] Introduction and Purpose: Smashing Magazine presents its monthly tradition of free desktop wallpapers for January 2026, designed to refresh workspaces and provide motivation for the new year. The article emphasizes small changes like new wallpapers can boost productivity during cold winter days.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;[2] Editorial Philosophy: The magazine respects artists&apos; creative freedom by not influencing wallpaper themes, allowing designers to express their emotions and experiences independently. The series has been running for over 14 years with contributions from global artists.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;[3] Featured Wallpaper Designs: The collection includes 17 unique wallpaper designs from artists worldwide, ranging from playful themes like &apos;Moonwalker&apos; and &apos;Yogabear&apos; to motivational pieces like &apos;Start Somewhere&apos; and &apos;Be Awesome Today&apos;. Each design is available in multiple resolutions with and without calendar versions.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;[4] Winter and New Year Themes: Several wallpapers celebrate winter imagery and January symbolism, including &apos;Winter Magic At Home,&apos; &apos;Open The Doors Of The New Year&apos; (referencing January&apos;s Latin origin &apos;ianua&apos; meaning door), and peaceful winter scenes. These designs capture seasonal warmth, new beginnings, and cozy winter moments.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;[5] Nature and Wildlife Designs: Multiple wallpapers feature animals and nature, including &apos;Bird Bird Bird Bird,&apos; &apos;Squirrel Appreciation Day,&apos; &apos;Cold... Penguins,&apos; and &apos;Peaceful Mountains&apos;. These designs celebrate wildlife and natural landscapes with playful and serene aesthetics.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;[6] Community Contribution: Artists from diverse countries including Spain, Serbia, United States, France, Belgium, and India contributed to the collection. The magazine actively invites designers to submit their work for future wallpaper posts, fostering a global creative community.</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
